# Lucas Brown

Pipeline TD

### Contact

**Address** 

Orlando, FL, 32825

**Phone** 

(747)-221-4849

E-mail

ImLucasBrown@gmail.com

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/imlucasbrown

## **Skills**

Python

Maya (pymel, cmds, om)

Linux

Rigging

Tech Anim

Pipeline TD/Technical artist with experience in full stack Python development, pipeline backend/tools, rigging, Pixar USD, and motion capture for animation and games. Expandable and easily deployable systems are king. Motivated and excited to work with supervisors, artists, and programmers to create a well oiled, easy to use, CG pipeline.

## **Work History**

2019-09 -

#### **Pipeline TD**

Current

Sunrise Productions, Cape Town

- Lead full stack Python developer on "NXT" (Node eXectuion Tree). A visual, node base, layered, code compositing application. Utilized Qt framework. Developed RPC/IPC backend for linear code execution in multiple DCCs.
- Pipeline backend development. CLI tools for asset creation and Python entry points for front end devs to utilize in various user interfaces..
- Pixar USD research and integration

2017-11 -2019-05

## **Character Rigger**

Pretty Simple Games, Paris, France

I developed rigs for characters, props, and vehicles to be used in a mobile game. On the pipeline side I took it upon myself to develop tools and workflows for the development of tools for asset creation/publishing.

On the animation side I developed tools for motion capture retargeting as well as easy QTE (Quick time event) creation and editing inside Maya.

2017-06 -

#### **Technical Artist**

2020-07

SVAD Productions, Collegedale, TN

- Rigged quadruped creatures for VR experience.
- Refactored legacy pipeline code to support newer versions of Maya.

## **Education**

2013-01 -2017-05

#### **Bachelor of Science: Animation**

Southern Adventist University - Collegedale, TN

• Awarded "Excellence in Character Technical Direction"